Finding aid to the Massachusetts Breast Cancer Coalition. Pioneer Valley Chapter records SSC.MS.00763
Sophia Smith Collection
Massachusetts Breast Cancer Coalition. Pioneer Valley Chapter records
1990-2004
Sophia Smith Collection
Massachusetts Breast Cancer Coalition. Pioneer Valley Chapter
SSC.MS.00763
1.75 linear feet (2 containers)
Founded in 1993 by a group of Western Massachusetts women concerned about issues related to breast cancer, the Pioneer Valley Chapter was associated with the statewide organization, the Massachusetts Breast Cancer Coalition (MBCC), until 1996 and in 2000 re-organized as the Cancer Connection which is still serving the Pioneer Valley in 2019. The collection contains correspondence, financial records, newspaper articles, meeting minutes and agendas, membership lists and programming materials.
Biographical Note
Founded in 1993 by a group of Western Massachusetts women concerned about issues related to breast cancer, the Pioneer Valley Chapter was associated with the statewide organization, the Massachusetts Breast Cancer Coalition (MBCC), until 1996 and in 2000 re-organized as the Cancer Connection which is still serving the Pioneer Valley in 2016. The MBCC Pioneer Valley Chapter engaged in community education through workshops, photography exhibits, and performances as a way to increase awareness and advocacy.
Conditions Governing Access
This collection is open for use with following restrictions on access: The donor has requested that researchers "....be mindful of the privacy of individual member names, addresses, and diagnoses".
Scope and Contents
Correspondence, financial records, newspaper articles, meeting minutes and agendas, membership lists and programming materials.
Immediate Source of Acquisition
This collection was donated to Smith College by Becky Jones, President of Cancer Connection, successor organization to Mass Breast Cancer Coalition, Pioneer Valley Chapter, which later became the Pioneer Valley Breast Cancer Network. It was donated on 12/07/05.
Breast -- Cancer -- History -- Sources; Breast -- Cancer -- Patients -- Sources; Women's Health -- United States; Women's Health -- United States -- Statistics; Women's health services -- History -- Sources; Women's health services -- Massachusetts -- History -- Sources; Women's health services -- United States -- History -- 20th century -- Sources; Cancer Connection; Agendas; Annual reports; articles; Brochures; clippings; correspondence; Ephemera; Financial records; Fliers; Fund raising; Invitations; Minutes; Newspapers; Notes; Organization files; Pamphlets; photographs; Plays; press releases; Programs; reports; scrapbooks; Speeches; Massachusetts Breast Cancer Coalition. Pioneer Valley Chapter
- 2016 accession, 1990-2004; Accession 2016-S-0001
  - Correspondence and notes, 1994-1996 (Box 1)
  - Overhead projector transparencies (and paper copies), 1994 (Box 1)
  - Newspaper articles, 1993-1994 (Box 1)
  - Brochures, pamphlets and press releases (in English and Spanish), 1994 (Box 1)
  - "Face to Face" photographic exhibit, 1994 (Box 1)
  - "Purple Breasts, a play in fifteen scenes", 1990 (Box 1)
  - Talking points (Box 1)
  - Contents of two scrapbooks, 1994-1995 (Box 1)
  - Speech, 1990's (Box 1)
  - Financial records and reports, 1994-1997; 2004 (Box 1)
  - Mailing lists (Box 1)
  - Meeting minutes and agendas, 1994-1998 (Box 1)
  - Tote bag (Box 1)
  - Flyers, 1993 (Box 1)
  - New York Times Sunday Magazine, 1993 (Box 1)